<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Code Files</title><link href="/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/blog/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/blog/</id><updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>How to Maximize X in Your Life</title><link href="/blog/how-to-maximize-anything-in-your-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Taylor Hornby</name></author><id>tag:/blog,2013-11-01:how-to-maximize-anything-in-your-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How to maximize X (success, happiness, skill, or whatever) in your life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every week, spend at least an hour reviewing what you did the previous week.
Think of what you could have done better to increase X even more. Apply the
things you find to the next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every month, spend at least an hour reviewing your review process. Are your
weekly reviews making you improve X? Think about how you could make your
review process better. Do you need more time for the weekly reviews? What
other changes to the reviews can you make so they're more effective? Apply
these changes in the next month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every year, spend at least an hour reviewing your monthly review of review
process. Are your monthly reviews improving the effectiveness of your weekly
reviews? How can you make your monthly reviews better? Apply these changes in
the next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every 5 years, review the yearly reviews in the same way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you graph y = X(t) as a curve, the days of your life represent actual
increases in the value of X. The weekly reviews represent increases in the slope
(first derivative) of X(t), making it increase faster. The monthly reviews
increases the rate at which the slope of X(t) increases (second derivative). The
yearly reviews increase the rate at which the rate at which the slope is
increasing (third derivative). The 5-year reviews increase the fourth
derivative, and so on, if you wish to apply more levels of review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this process to be the best a human being can do to approximate
exponential growth of some property of themselves within their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="life"></category></entry></feed>