<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Code Files</title><link href="/blog2/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/blog2/feeds/security.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/blog2/</id><updated>2013-08-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Enabling TLS v1.1 on Firefox 23</title><link href="/blog2/enabling-tls-11-on-firefox-version-23.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Taylor Hornby</name></author><id>tag:/blog2,2013-08-09:enabling-tls-11-on-firefox-version-23.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Change the following settings in Firefox's &lt;a class="reference external" href="about:config"&gt;about:config&lt;/a&gt; to enable TLS v1.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Enabling TLS 1.1 in Firefox 23" src="https://defuse.ca/images/ff23-tls.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a new tab and type &lt;a class="reference external" href="about:config"&gt;about:config&lt;/a&gt; into the address bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search for tls.version.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set security.tls.version.max to 2. This enables TLS 1.1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set security.tls.version.min to 1. This disables SSL 3.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be aware that setting tls.version.max to 3 will enable TLS v1.2 in a future
release of Firefox, but setting it to 3 in version 23 actually makes it fall
back to using &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; TLS 1.0. So for now, set it to 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image was contributed by &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/voodooKobra"&gt;&amp;#64;voodooKobra&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="firefox"></category></entry><entry><title>What is DDoS? (Guest Post)</title><link href="/blog2/what-is-ddos.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Breshie</name></author><id>tag:/blog2,2013-05-12:what-is-ddos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a guest post by BreShiE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DDoS attacks are becoming more and more frequent in today's world, with any
average person being able to download or purchase such tools from online, public
forums. You may have heard about the self proclaimed hacktivist group
&amp;quot;Anonymous&amp;quot; and their infamous take-downs of websites such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operation_Payback"&gt;MasterCard,
PayPal and The Bank of America&lt;/a&gt;. Well, these websites were taken offline for
a period of time by an attack known as &amp;quot;DDoS&amp;quot;, but what is DDoS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DDoS&lt;/strong&gt; stands for &lt;strong&gt;Distributed Denial of Service&lt;/strong&gt;. DDoS attacks work by
collecting multiple infected machines or servers with certain scripts, or
malware, intended to send data from the infected server or home connection to
a victims. This means the attacker can overload the victim connection, by
flooding it with loads and loads of dummy data, eventually causing the victim
connection to overload, &amp;quot;knocking&amp;quot; the connection offline and making it
unresponsive. See the below diagram for an example of this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="/images/breshie-ddos.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the above diagram, the attacker sends a command to the
servers/PCs that are under his/her control, which then send the dummy data to
the victim connection and overloads the connection, making it hard or impossible
for the victim's users to communicate with the victim. There's also what is
known as &amp;quot;DoS&amp;quot; which is often not as strong as a DDoS attack, but if the
attacker is using a server with a strong connection, this attack can still be
devastating. One thing to &lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt; would be that there are companies which fight
to prevent this exact attack and that is why you never see big sites like eBay,
YouTube and Google go down. With this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-17472447"&gt;huge scare about &amp;quot;hackers being able to
take down the internet&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, it's baloney. The only way it would be possible, is
if the data-centers were to be physically blown up, not DDoS attacks via the
internet.  If you wish to know more on this subject, visit &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_denial_of_service#Distributed_attack"&gt;Wikipedia's page on
DDoS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ddos"></category></entry></feed>